

PROFILE

Highly skilled Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience building quality software applications at scale. Strong communicator and problem-solver with a track record of delivering robust and extensible infrastructure. Experienced in working with complex federal & agency regulations in financial and healthcare sectors.

CONTACT

PHONE:

(732)-682-0887

WEBSITE:

https://www.firas.casa linkedin.com/in/fsattar

EMAIL

firas.a.sattar@gmail.com

SKILLS

Languages:

Python, Java, C, C#, C++, Go, HTML/CSS, Javascript

Frameworks/Libraries/Toolsets:

FastAPI, Flask, Spring, numpy, pandas, fastai, PyTorch, opencv, Jupyter, MATLAB

Database/Search:

Oracle, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch

Cloud/Infrastructure:

Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, AWS, GCC

HOBBIES

Visual art (painting, drawing, ceramics), recording music (guitar, piano, singing), hiking, nature, travel

FIRAS SATTAR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EDUCATION

Rutgers University – New Brunswick, School of Arts and Sciences Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – Mathematics Minor Sept. 2012 – May 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Work

2022 - Present

• Tech consulting for **Danni Pose Studios** and mentoring on **codementor.io**

Principal Product Support Engineer, Feathr Inc.

October 2023 - October 2024

- Feature development, hotfixes, enhancements for a nonprofit marketing platform. Software engineering with an emphasis on customer success.
- Lead triage team in identifying patterns in incoming tickets and resolving underlying code issues before they became outages.

Fin3 Technologies Inc., Blockchain Engineer

March 2022 - July 2022

Fin3 is a startup focused on connecting banking cores with blockchains. Their Blockchain Interface System (BIS) allows customers to seamlessly convert traditional currency to tokenized stablecoin for transacting on the blockchain.

- Orchestrated integration of banking software with payment networks like Stellar and Provenance, collaborating with third-party development teams to meet strict regulatory requirements.
- Built a robust framework for custodial wallet management to handle secure creation and cycling of keys.
- Increased developer efficiency by automating CI/CD workflows using GitHub Actions.

IBIS Inc., Software Engineer

Nov 2017 - March 2022

IBIS specializes in medical imaging solutions, primarily in the regulated Clinical Research space. Using a robust clinical data management platform, IBIS provides high-end data management solutions to the life sciences/healthcare communities.

- Conducted research and development on medical image de-identification, resulting in securing a \$400,000 grant. (SBIR 411 and 427)
- Developed Al-powered anonymizer for DICOM medical images, facilitating HIPAA-compliant use of data in cancer research applications.
- Created containerized Python application for secure medical data transmission and retrieval using Elasticsearch, meeting sub-second performance requirements.
- Contributed to successful audit through system testing and validation efforts.
 (21CFR Part 11)

IDT Corporation (Products and Services Platform), Software Engineer Jul. 2016 – Nov 2017

The Products and Services Platform (PSP) is responsible for 47% of IDT revenue. As a member of the development team supporting PSP:

- Created configurable call simulators for testing flagship calling app Boss Revolution Mobile.
- Developed a Java application to assess customer call, data, and SMS eligibility based on standing and initiate account status changes.
- Built a full-stack user account management application using React.js.